# Clayton W. Seitz, PhD

# cwseitz@iu.edu cwseitz.github.io

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

I maintain a diverse background and specialize in the development and application of machine learning models. Recently, I have developed deep generative models as well as analytical probabilistic methods for modeling imaging datasets. These models have been applied to fluorescence microscopy to fuel biological discovery.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Doctor of Philosopy, Physics

Indiana University

Thesis: Advancing super-resolution microscopy for quantitative in-vivo imaging of chromatin nanodomains

# Master of Science, Biophysics

University of Chicago

Thesis: Stable cell assembly formation in excitatory-inhibitory neural networks

## Bachelor of Science, Physics, Magna Cum Laude

Indiana University
Minor: Mathematics

#### Bachelor of Science, Informatics, Magna Cum Laude

Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering, Indiana University Concentration: Mathematics

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Graduate Researcher

2022-Present

Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

- Designed diffusion models/score-based generative models and general computer vision techniques (object detection, segmentation, etc.) in PyTorch for modeling image datasets in super-resolution fluorescence microscopy
- Developed general probabilistic models for high-dimensional imaging datasets and associated Bayesian methods for statistical inference tasks
- Developed novel microscopy systems for super-resolution imaging of living cells
- Investigated the impact of point mutations of epigenetic proteins on the structure of nucleosome nanodomains and complement experimental data with molecular dynamics simulations

#### Graduate Researcher

2020-2022

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

- Performed Monte Carlo simulations of spiking neural networks to relate neural network architecture to spiking dynamics
- Utilized fluorescence microscopy to measure temporal dynamics of calcium concentration in MIN6 cells

### Research Assistant

2019-2020

Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

• Developed an package in Python for high-throughput image processing

# Information Systems Intern

Liberty Mutual Insurance

- Wrote Python scripts to automate attestation testing of web facing servers
- Assisted in configuration of web application firewalls (WAFs)

#### AWARDS

NIH Graduate Training Fellowship University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

2020

2016

Travel Award and Lightning Talk Invitation Physical Sciences in Oncology - Minneapolis, MN 2019

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship

2016-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Quantum enhanced localization microscopy with a single photon avalanche diode array. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz<sup>†</sup>, Donghong Fu<sup>†</sup>, Mengyuan Liu, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. BRD4 phosphorylation regulates the structure of chromatin nanodomains. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Uncertainty-aware localization microscopy by variational diffusion. In Review. 2024

> Maelle Locatelli<sup>†</sup>, Josh Lawrimore<sup>†</sup>, Hua Lin<sup>†</sup>, Sarvath Sanaullah, Clayton Seitz, Dave Segall, Paul Kefer, Salvador Moreno Naike, Benton Lietz, Rebecca Anderson, Julia Holmes, Chongli Yuan, George Holzwarth, Bloom Kerry, Jing Liu, Keith D Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi. DNA damage reduces heterogeneity and coherence of chromatin motions. PNAS 12 July 2022; 119 (29): 1-11

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International 15 January 2022; 46 (5): 683-700

> Wenting Wu, Farooq Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 25 October 2021; 71 (1): 116 - 127

> Clayton Seitz, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. Cytokine-induced transcriptional memory is evident in the kinetics of transcriptional bursts. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2022

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2020

 $\begin{array}{ll} \textbf{TECHNICAL} & Programming\ Languages\ \&\ Software:\ Linux,\ Bash,\ Python,\ R,\ PyTorch,\ C/C++,\\ \textbf{SKILLS} & SQL,\ LaTeX,\ Git,\ SLURM \end{array}$